Thank you.
Good morning, Canvas Community Church.
Man, that was awesome.
I don't even need to, like, try to, like, recycle that to get a better response.
That was great.
Good morning, everybody.
Glad to see everybody is here.
Hey, I just want to give a shout-out to Doc in the back.
He never gets any props.
But he sent me up here with a microphone ready to go.
I didn't have to hit any buttons.
He made it as easy as possible, so he knew who he was dealing with.
My name's Dave Ballinger.
It is my pleasure to welcome you to church today.
If you are a first-time guest, and I know somebody in the front row who's a first-time guest right over here, say hi to Aiden, everybody.
First-time guest.
He sent his wife, what's your name?
Aiden and Amanda.
They got married yesterday.
They got baptized yesterday in a river, and they're coming to church today for the first time at our church.
So how awesome.
What an awesome day.
So for guys like you, if it's your first time, we would love to connect with you, even more than we did in the lobby.
There is a box in the back with some cards you can fill out.
Let us know that you're here.
If you guys need prayer, want to serve, just get to know the church, that's a way to do it.
And also, there's some people at the welcome desk in the back.
They're very scary people, but they have gifts.
So I would hit them up.
Get your gift.
No, they're awesome people.
They're amazing.
Some of the coolest people I know work at the Welcome Center.
All right, moving on.
Cultivate.
My hair blew forward when Donovan did that.
Cultivate Youth Group is having its annual back-to-school float trip again this year.
Grades 6 through 12 are welcome to join at Watermelon Park on August 23rd.
That's a Saturday.
Drinks and snacks will be provided.
Please sign up online.
We have an app, so that's where you would do that.
You can also do the QR code that's up on the screen.
Next, about fires.
Wild at Heart Fires is an authentic monthly gathering where men experience God through the stories of other men around a campfire.
It is actually very cool.
I've been to a couple.
Come out this Wednesday at 6.30 p.m. at Corey Smith's house.
Is Corey here?
He's camping.
He's here somewhere.
He's not here.
Okay.
Hit me up.
I'll help you out.
Hit up Ken Sanders.
He can give you some information about how to get to Corey's.
If you are interested in going to fires, and you're a dude.
Corey Smith in the house.
There he is in the back.
So, if you want to go to his house and hang out, it's a dude right back there.
All right.
Just any time.
Just show up at his house.
He loves that.
Man, this might be exciting.
If you are a parent of a C3 kid, they're having their second annual mystery bus trip on Saturday, August 30th.
Get this time frame.
10 a.m. to 8 p.m.
Parents are like, take my money.
There are a limited number of seats available, so sign up your third, fourth, and fifth graders as soon as possible.
I would definitely get on that.
This promises to be an event they won't forget.
I've seen pictures of the past one last year.
It is amazing.
The bus is awesome, and the kids are going to have a blast.
Tara Holmes.
Where's Tara?
Come here.
So, she can walk while I talk.
We are hosting a fundraiser for Blazing Hope Ranch called Free Her to Hope.
Join us.
There it is.
Join us on September 20th, 2025, from 5 to 10 p.m.
at the Greenwood Volunteer Fire Hall in Winchester.
We'll have dinner, a cash bar, a speaker.
Ranch co-founder Jolene Haggard will be there.
They're going to have a silent auction, dancing.
And DJ MJ is going to be there.
That's not Michael Jackson, though.
That's E-M-J-A-Y.
It's a different MJ, so don't bring any cards to get signed.
Tickets are $50 per person or $400 for a table with 10 seats.
So, if you have a group of people you'd like to go with, you can do that.
Check out the event on the website.
Details are there to purchase tickets.
And also, I'll let you do this part.
So, in your bulletin, there is a beautiful little flyer that has two QR codes on it.
One of them is to be able to buy tickets, and it links you to the event page that's part
of the Blazing Hope website, but it's got all the details about the party.
So, get your tickets soon, because we can only have so many people in the fire hall.
The other one, because, yeah, fire code, it's the fire hall.
But the other one is to help with the silent auction.
So, silent auctions are a great way for us to raise money, and so we want some really
great stuff.
The QR code will link you to a sign-up genius, and if there's a basket that you think you could
help put together, sign up for that.
If you work somewhere that would like to donate a service, or you own a business that would
like to donate a service for us to include in our silent auction, please let us know.
Jill Keister is heading up our silent auction, but you can talk to me,
Jill, you can talk to Molly Corbett, you can talk to Sam Smith, or you can talk to Helen
Reithart.
We're all kind of part of that team.
So, please, if you have any interest, please help us so we can have the best fundraiser possible.
Thank you.
Great job, Tara.
Okay, we're wrapping up here.
If you want these announcements and much more, please sign up for our weekly e-newsletter.
Why would you want it any way other than this?
I don't know.
But if you don't have time, yeah, you can get the e-newsletter.
You'll receive information about upcoming events, links for registrations, and other church news
delivered right to your inbox.
Ways to give.
So, we have a couple ways to give.
As followers of Jesus, we think that everybody should be giving some of their money to somebody
else who needs it.
One way, you don't have to give it here, but we encourage you to give somewhere.
If you do choose to give here, thank you.
We have a lot of faithful givers, and we appreciate that.
There's a QR code that you can use to donate.
I don't see it up on the screen right now, but there is one.
Also, the offering box is in the back, right next to the clock.
So, if you want to do it old school, check, or just cash.
You can drop it in there.
Or if you download the app, you can give online.
That's what I do.
That's it.
I'm done.
We're going to transition to worship.
All right.
Woo!
Thank you, Dave.
Good morning, Canvas Community Church.
Hey, I was a little disappointed.
You started talking about Cultivate, and our Cultivate Youth section is there in the back
with the big banner and the black chairs, and you guys didn't even cheer.
So, let's try Cultivate Youth Float Trip.
All right.
Now you know what to do.
Cultivate Back to School Float Trip.
I give up.
Let's love on God today.
Let's praise his holy name.
Let's clear our schedule.
Let's clear what's going on later today.
Let's take this time to be in the moment, to be present, and to worship our God and Savior.
To you, oh, God, I lift my soul.
In you, oh, God, I place my trust.
And do not let me be put to shame.
Don't let my enemies triumph over me.
My hope is in you, oh, God, I place my hope in you, oh, God, I place my trust in you, oh, God.
Show me your ways.
Guide me in truth in all my days.
My hope is in you, oh, God, I place my trust in you, oh, God.
I am alone here with your love.
You are, oh, God, my salvation.
You will guard my life and rescue me.
My hope is in you, oh, God, I place my trust in you, oh, God, I place my trust in you.
Show me your ways, guide me in truth in all my days.
My hope is in you.
Oh, God, I place my trust in you, oh, God, I place my trust in you.
Show me your ways, yeah, yeah.
Guide me in truth in all my days.
My hope is in you.
Show me your ways, guide me in truth in all my days.
Show me your ways, guide me in truth.
In all my days.
My hope is in you.
how great the chasm that lay between us.
How great the chasm that lay between us.
How high the mountain I could not climb.
In desperation I turned to heaven and spoke your name into the night.
Then through the darkness your loving kindness tore through the shadows of my soul.
The work is finished.
The end is written.
Praise the one who set me free
Hallelujah
Death has lost its grip on me
You have broken every chain
There's salvation in your name
Jesus Christ, my living hope
Hallelujah
Praise the one who set me free
Death has lost its grip on me
You have broken every chain
There's salvation in your name
Jesus Christ, my living hope
Then came the morning
That sealed the promise
Your very body
Began to breathe
Out of the silence
The roaring lion
Declared the grave
Has no claim on me
Yes
Then came the morning
That sealed the promise
Your very body
Began to breathe
Out of the silence
The roaring lion
Declared the grave
Has no claim on me
And Jesus
Yours
Is the victory
Hallelujah
Praise the one who set me free
Death has lost its grip on me
You have broken every chain
There's salvation in your name
Jesus Christ, my living hope
Hallelujah
Praise the one who set me free
Death has lost its grip on me
You have broken every chain
There's salvation in your name
Jesus Christ, my living hope
God, you are my living hope
All righty, this morning's Scripture reading is Matthew 11, 25 through 30
At the time Jesus said, I praise you, Father, Lord of heaven and earth
Because you have hidden these things from the wise
And learned and revealed them to little children
Yes, Father, for this is what you were pleased to do
All things have been committed to me, my Father
No one knows the Son except the Father
And no one knows the Father except for the Son
And those to whom the Son chooses to reveal him
Come to me, O you who are weary
And burdened, and I will give you rest
Take my yoke upon you and learn from me
For I am gentle and humble in heart
And you will find rest for your souls
For my yoke is easy and my burden is light
Are you hurting and broken within?
Overwhelmed by the weight of your sin
Jesus is calling
Have you come to the end of yourself?
Do you thirst for a drink from the well?
Jesus is calling
Oh, come to the altar
The Father's arms are open wide
Forgiveness was bought with
The precious blood of Jesus Christ
Leave behind your friends and mistakes
Come today, there's no reason to wait
Jesus is calling
Bring your sorrows
Bring your sorrows and drink them for joy
From the ashes through the light that's born
Jesus is calling
Oh, come to the altar
The Father's arms are open wide
Forgiveness was bought with
The precious blood of Jesus Christ
Oh, what a Savior
Isn't he wonderful
Sing hallelujah
Christ is risen
We bow down before him
For he is Lord of all
Sing hallelujah
Christ is risen
Oh, what a Savior
Isn't he wonderful
Sing hallelujah
Christ is risen
Oh, come to the altar
Bow down before him
For he is Lord of all
Sing hallelujah
Christ is risen
Oh, come to the altar
The altar, the Father's arms are open wide.
Forbiveness was bought with the precious blood of Jesus Christ.
Oh, come to the altar, the Father's arms are open wide.
Bear your cross as you wait for the crown.
Tell the world of the treasure you've found.
The altar, the altar, the altar, the altar, the altar, the altar, the altar, the altar, the altar.
Thank you.
I baptize you in the name of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit.
Oh, what a Savior, isn't he wonderful?
I baptize you in the name of the Father, the Son, and the Son, and the Son, and the Son.
I baptize you in the name of the Father, the Son, and the Holy Spirit.
Oh, what a Savior, isn't he wonderful?
Sing hallelujah.
Christ is risen.
For he is Lord of all.
Say hallelujah.
Christ is risen.
I baptize you in the name of the Father, the Son, and the Son.
I baptize you in the name of the Father, the Son.
Is there anything better than that?
No.
You guys are worse than Cultivate.
Is there anything better than that?
Woo!
This morning is exciting for a number of reasons, two of which we just got to celebrate in that
tank.
And so really excited about this morning.
And another opportunity that I'm excited about is we are introducing one of our very own members
to preach her very first sermon on this stage this morning.
So I'm really excited about that.
So in just a minute after I say some lovely things about Jill Keister, she's going to join us.
This opportunity for her to speak really came a couple of months ago.
I was preaching a sermon just talking about how our church is not my church, it's our church.
And how the church is made up of believers who all have different gifts and all are called to use those gifts in whatever way God is inviting them into.
And as I was preaching, Jill had some work of the Spirit going on in her life.
And Jill has been a regular Bible teacher for a long time.
She's taught at women's retreats.
She's led our women's ministry for a long time.
And always had the gift of teaching.
Always had this opportunity to use it in different settings.
But never really thought Sunday morning was an option until I kind of said like, hey, this is not my church.
This is our church.
And so after that we had some conversations and we've been working together for a while and just excited about this opportunity.
And really, I'm excited about this opportunity for a couple of reasons.
Two of our core values.
Number one is we rely on the written and living word of God.
We are a people of the Word.
The Word is important to us.
And what I love about our church is that's not just a few of us are committed to the Word.
But a lot of us are committed to the Word.
Jill being one of many of those who are committed to being able to study and understand and interpret the text on their own.
And not just have somebody do it for them, but to do the work themselves, to be equipped to do that.
And the second is that we equip the saints to do the work of the ministry that God is calling them to.
And the thing that I love, one of the things I love most about our church is I plan to, if you all don't fire me and the Lord doesn't like rip me from this place, I plan to like get old and gray here.
And I'm getting gray already, so it's really, it's not that far away.
But the beautiful thing I love about our church is if I were to get hit by a bus tomorrow, we have people.
That's my mom.
She says, stop.
Providence of God.
If I get hit by a bus, you know, it happens.
We have a number of people who know how to study the Scriptures, who are equipped to teach God's people God's Word.
And that is, that is not by accident.
And that is not a reality of many churches across the country.
Many churches across the country are reliant on one person who got shipped away to get a Bible college degree and came back and everybody waits for that person to give them the word.
We are not that people.
And I think that's a beautiful, incredible thing.
Like if I get hit by a bus, you guys don't have to hire somebody for a while.
You can take your time.
You can find the perfect candidate because we have people who are equipped in their gifting to do the thing that God's called them to do.
And so Jill, I'm excited for you.
You can start making your way here.
Excited to hear her.
And I'm sure she's nervous because anytime I step onto a new stage, anytime I do something new for the first time, I'm nervous.
So be praying for her and give her the best listening ears you have.
Sound good?
And to be able to participate in this summer series on the Psalms.
And as we've learned, the Psalms speak for us.
And I think that's what we're going to find this morning.
If you do not know my family much, just a little bit about us.
We moved here in 2017.
We had to move for my husband Aaron's job.
And that was a fairly easy move.
But most moves are not always easy.
Would anyone else agree with me?
This is not an easy thing, right?
So we've probably all of us in this room at some point or another have moved, you know, out of your parents' home, off to college.
Maybe you're downsizing.
But it's not easy.
And we had another move once before where we again had to move for his job.
The company that he worked for required that he lived in the area that he serviced.
And so it wasn't an option.
It was we had to move.
Now, this was the first time we were selling our -- it was the first time selling a home.
So we chose a realtor and we got our house on the market.
And not too long, we had an offer.
We had it under contract.
But it fell through.
And so we were like, okay, we're all right.
We're okay.
And then we got another offer.
And so we put it under contract.
And now let me tell you, this was by the same guy who put the contract on the house the first time.
And he came to us and he promised us that finances were in order.
He took care of what the problem was the first time.
And we were going to be okay this time.
Okay.
Sure.
First time mistake, right?
So anyway, just to also let you know, we had two small children at the time.
Our girls were only three and two.
And we had a puppy.
And so as you can imagine, trying to be ready for showings and packing a house
and trying to keep things normal for the kids was a little tough.
So long story short, this second contract fell through.
We looked at our realtor and we were like, look, we can't accept another offer from this guy.
If his name comes across again with an offer, we are not accepting.
We can't.
We can't do this.
We were worn out.
We were exhausted.
But yet we had hope that something better was going to come along.
So finally, again, you know, making sure the house is ready.
You have those last minute showings, right?
We'll be there in an hour.
Oh, let's put everything in a laundry basket and shove it in the car.
Let's go.
And so we got a contract.
A woman placed this contract.
We accepted that offer, placed the contract, whatever.
And everything was moving smoothly.
We thought this was all good.
And we got to the day before closing.
We have everything on the trailer.
We have it loaded, our girls' beds, the last minute toys and food in your house.
We were ready to pull out the driveway.
And I get a phone call.
The only words I heard was, Jill, I'm so sorry.
I fell to my knees in that moment.
I couldn't stand under the weight and under the pressure of all that was happening.
The only response I had was to fall.
I had nothing else.
And the only thing I could keep thinking was, God, why?
Why is this happening to us?
What are you doing?
The realtor kept talking.
Come to find out, the woman that placed that contract on the house was the mother of the guy who placed the first two contracts.
She didn't have her finances in order either.
I was done.
I took one look at my husband.
I said, Aaron, I don't care.
We are not moving back into that house.
You know, the girls were so excited because we had plans to build a house.
And we were going to live with my in-laws in the time period.
And so they were super excited to be able to go and live with Granny and Papaw, right?
There's no way I could have told them, no, sorry, that's not happening.
We've got to move back into our house again.
I said, we're done.
I was so deeply distressed.
The emotional roller coaster was more than I could take.
That moment on my knees under the weight of all that had happened.
Again, it was automatic.
I didn't even think about it.
I just went to that posture.
I imagine many of you have had moments like that in your life when everything has come crashing down and you too have felt this.
We're more likely to surrender and allow God to take over in these times because we have nothing left.
So we look to the Scriptures for comfort.
Most of the times we can look in Psalms because, again, they speak for us.
Look at Psalm 143.
And I believe that we see David in a very similar situation of crying out before the Lord in this Psalm.
So if you'll turn with me, if you have your Bibles, we'll also have it up on the screen so that you can read along.
I'm going to be reading from the ESV.
And as we read this, I would love for you to think about what might have been David's posture when he wrote this.
Hear my prayer, O Lord.
Give ear to my pleas for mercy.
In your faithfulness, answer me.
In your righteousness.
Enter not into judgment with your servant, for no one living is righteous before you.
For the enemy has pursued my soul.
He has crushed my life to the ground.
He has made me sit in darkness like those long dead.
Therefore, my spirit faints within me.
My heart within me is appalled.
I remember the days of old.
I meditate on all that you have done, and I ponder the work of your hands.
I stretch out my hands to you like my soul thirsts for you like a parched land.
Answer me quickly, O Lord.
My spirit fails.
Hide not your face from me, lest I be like those who go down to the pit.
Let me hear in the morning of your steadfast love, for in you I trust.
Make me know the way I should go, for to you I lift up my soul.
Deliver me from my enemies, O Lord.
I have fled to you for refuge.
Teach me to do your will, for you are my God.
Let your good spirit lead me on level ground.
For your namesake, O Lord, preserve my life.
In your righteousness, bring my soul out of trouble.
In your steadfast love, you will cut off my enemies, and you will destroy all the adversaries of my soul.
For I am your servant.
Let's pray.
Father God, we thank you for your word.
We thank you that we can come to these words and use them as our own prayers to you.
God, today we ask that you open up our eyes and allow us to see you this morning.
In Jesus' name we pray.
Amen.
Now, I love to be able to share with others what God has shown me, what he has taught me.
And sometimes I can get a little excited.
If you've been to a women's retreat, you know that I can get excited.
So, I promise I'm going to try really hard to not talk fast and get too excited.
But, if I do, I'm just going to ask that you guys do as Ryan asks and that you guys just listen fast.
Is that okay?
Okay, cool.
Alright, we're good.
Okay, so my plan is to kind of work through this psalm verse by verse.
But there's a few things I want to point out first.
A lot of times in Scripture, when we see someone crying out to God in the midst of hardship,
Scripture labels that as lamenting.
Lament is that expression of disappointment and grief and sorrow.
And I believe we've all been there at some point, yeah?
Psalm 143 is a psalm of lament.
And so I am trusting that this will be meaningful to each of us in some way this morning.
This psalm is one of the seven penitential psalms.
Those are the songs of confession that were historically sung on Ash Wednesday.
As you may know, Ash Wednesday is the start of the Lentil season.
It's during that season of Lent that we look to God and we wonder who we are before him.
And we look to the hope that he offers.
David even finds himself in this psalm crying out and he's able to have hope that he can hang on to when he sees the faithfulness of God.
This psalm was also probably written when either he was being chased by King Saul or by his son Absalom.
But in either situation, we find that his distress is brought on by a person, by an enemy.
David describes his circumstances, and we're going to look in verses 3 and 4.
I have hope on the slide.
Some of these words are highlighted.
I've also pulled from other translations.
But these words are chased, pursued, persecuted, crushed, knocked down.
His spirit faints.
He's overwhelmed, paralyzed with fear, defeated, and appalled.
Have we felt this?
What posture have we found ourselves in in those times?
I know I want to curl up in the corner and cry, right?
But I think it's interesting that David didn't start there.
When we jump back up to verses 1 and 2, David cries out boldly to God.
He says, give ear, hear my prayer.
Other translations, listen, pay attention.
If you look at these from a grammar or a language arts perspective, these are commands.
David is commanding this of God.
And sometimes some of us might be sitting there thinking, I can't command that of God.
Who am I?
Like, there's no way.
But I think it's important for us to look.
This is a Hebrew format of poetic parallelism that David uses throughout the psalm.
The first line is making a statement while the second one is emphasizing the first.
Hear my prayer.
Give ear.
He uses it even when he's describing God.
He says, in your faithfulness, in your righteousness.
David is praying to God with an urgency for God to hear him because of his circumstances.
He pleads with God not to judge him because he, nor anyone, is righteous.
Which alludes to the character of God that only God is righteous.
David's confident and bold prayer is acceptable because David knows God's character.
God has been faithful, just.
He has provided.
He is righteous.
David has seen it.
David has experienced it.
And so he is praying and pleading with God to do it again.
Look at verses five and six.
He says, I remember the days of old.
They may have been in the past, but he can remember them because they're worth remembering.
There's parts of our story that are worth remembering.
And then there's parts of our story that are not worth remembering.
The things that God has done in our life, the work of God in his hand are the things that are worth remembering.
In this passage, David reminds us to meditate on the work of his hands.
To ponder them.
These things take time.
It's not just a passing thought.
It has to sink in.
It has to affect us.
That's what their, that's what the whole goal.
Does it affect how we live when we've pondered the things that God has done in our life?
I encourage you this week as you're reading Scripture, as you're spending time with the Lord.
As you begin to meditate on the things of God, to write them down.
Journal them.
Put them in your journal, Jay.
Barrett's got, I don't know how many journals, right?
Okay.
But honestly, there is a connection that happens in your brain when you write things down.
And you can remember it better.
So spend the time and write them down.
And then place them where you're going to see them.
So that it's a constant reminder of what God has done in your life.
You are continually thinking on them because you're seeing them and you've got them written on your heart because you've written them down and they're already in there.
They're stuck.
Right?
That is how David knew God's character and it shaped his prayer life.
Look at verse six.
David's response to God's hand in his life was to stretch out his own hand.
This posture was a common prayer posture.
It was a posture of hope.
It's the physical posture that affected his spiritual life.
Sir Richard Baker, who Charles Spurgeon quotes, he says this.
I stretch forth my hand unto thee as if I were in hope thou wouldest take me by the hand and draw me to thee.
The work of God's hand gives us hope.
God's hand is always extended towards us.
Do we fully extend our hand back to God whether it's in our posture or in our asking?
David's circumstances led him to God, not away from God.
Only God can satisfy.
Only God could bring about the safety and the rescue that David needed.
We too need to be mindful of our personal reach to God.
After verse six, we see Selah and we have learned that that is an instrumental interlude or meaning pause.
So it's a cue for reflection.
David built it in and it's like, okay, here's your clue.
Take time and think about this.
Here's my situation.
Here's God's provisions.
Yes, my situation is very real.
But I'm going to trust and rely on God's provision.
I'm going to rely on his character.
When you're praying through this prayer, pause and think about your circumstance and God's faithfulness in your life up to this point.
After a time of reflection, David comes back in and he appeals to God in verse seven.
He says, answer me quickly.
David wanted an answer.
Now he wanted a rescue.
Now he was tired.
He was worn out.
He didn't have anything left.
I know that even in our circumstance, I wanted an answer right away.
The stress of selling our house led me down a very hard and unhealthy spiral.
A place where I felt horrible all the time.
I couldn't eat.
I lost weight.
Medicines wouldn't help.
Doctors didn't know what to do.
I wanted relief right away, but it didn't come.
David continues and he asks God not to hide his face from him.
After he has spent time remembering and pondering and meditating on God and the works of his hand, David wants to hold on to God's presence.
You guys know when you spend time in the presence of God, it is something you don't ever want to leave.
It is so good.
And David is saying that he knows that if God turns his face away, he's not going to make it.
And that thought alone drives David to despair.
David Gusick says it like this.
He says, God, with your face, I can face anything.
Without your face, I can't face a thing.
It's like the warmth of the sun.
It's mist when it's gone.
Imagine with me for a minute as I take a water.
What would it be like if we were that in tune to the presence of God on a day-to-day or a moment-by-moment basis?
What would it be like if we were fixed on his presence in our life?
Anybody get excited?
If you think about the possibilities of that, I know I do.
But yet, I have to ask.
In our culture, have we allowed ourselves to be immune to God's presence and the work that he's doing in our lives each and every moment?
We go through the hustle and the bustle and we get in our routine and we do what we do.
Are we aware?
As I was working on this section, I spent time praying myself, God, open up my eyes.
Allow me to see your hand.
Allow me to see where you're working, what you're doing.
Not only in my life, in my family's life, in my friends, in my circumstances.
And the coolest thing happened.
A moment later, literally like a minute, I got a text message from a friend who said,
"I was prostrate on the floor crying this morning because of the goodness and the mercy of God in my life."
What an answer to prayer.
God heard my prayer.
He answered it because someone else was obedient to share it with us.
You see, something physical was happening in her body.
There was a healing taking place in her body.
And it impacted her spiritual life.
The posture of gratitude, prostrate on the floor, is beautiful.
Our physical position affects our spiritual position.
Think about the posture that we automatically go into when we are lamenting.
Think about the posture in that pool this morning.
They made a spiritual commitment that led to a physical commitment.
And we got to witness that.
We got to see God working in their lives in that moment.
What an honor.
Whew.
God is working all around us.
Do we see it?
God's presence is all around us.
Do we sense it?
God does hear us.
He does answer us.
David knew that God listened.
And that's why he said, "Listen and give ear."
Please pay attention.
He knew that about God.
He says, "Let me hear in the morning of your steadfast love."
You know what's encouraging about that?
The night and the darkness won't last.
That's right.
David is putting...
Oh, let me tell you this.
Not only will the darkness not last.
But I know that there are some of us in this room who have felt like, "I have asked, and I have asked, and I have asked, and I have prayed, and I have prayed, but I'm not getting an answer."
But I want you to see that there is hope.
Because God is who he is.
David puts his trust in a faithful, proven God, and not in anything else.
And it's not his own desire.
David puts his trust in a faithful, proven God.
And not in anything else.
And it's not his own desire.
David puts his trust in a faithful, proven God.
And not in anything else.
And it's not his own desire.
David puts his trust in a faithful, proven God.
And not in anything else.
And it's not his own desires.
And it's not anything of the world.
The trust that David puts in God leads him to ask for God to make known to him the way that he should go.
David knows God's character and can ask this of him because he knows God will do it.
This aligns even with other Scriptures.
In Matthew 7, it tells us, "Ask and it will be given to you."
Psalm 34 says, "When the righteous cry out for help."
The Lord hears and delivers them out of all of their trouble.
James talks about asking several times.
If you do not have, because you do not ask.
If you lack wisdom, ask.
Ask in faith without doubting.
Ask.
God will show and make known to us where we are to go and where we are to go.
And what we are to do when we ask in faith.
But I know.
In the asking.
And in the waiting.
It can be long.
And painful.
And slow.
I experienced that too.
In the pain.
Of not feeling well.
Half the time I didn't feel good enough to even take care of my children.
God why?
David had faith because he knew God's character.
I know I have said that several times today.
But that is what I want you to take home today.
Knowing God's character impacts our prayer life and how we live and or it should.
The more we understand God's nature, the greater the change in our life.
Read that again.
The more we understand God's nature, the greater the change in our lives.
God's nature, the greater the change in our lives.
We see that when David fled to God for refuge, it restates that only God can satisfy our rescue.
Nothing that we turn to will provide what we need or give deliverance that we need.
David is willing and ready to do God's will.
He says, teach me to do your will.
Again, he's asking and he has the faith to boldly ask.
He says, you are my God and your spirit is good.
He's experienced this.
David experienced the spirit of God.
Are you guys getting this?
If David could experience it and know that God's spirit was good, how much more can we experience it?
Because we as believers have the infiltration of the Holy Spirit in us.
Are we aware?
Are we paying attention to that presence that's all around us?
David asks to be led on level ground.
And I like the way Eugene Peterson words it.
He says, level pasture land.
That takes us back to Psalm 23, which we've looked at this summer as well.
That's a term that David would have resonated with.
It's that place where we're provided all we need.
Rest.
Food.
Comfort.
And safety.
We, our family, eventually landed in the pasture land.
We did sell our house eventually.
We completed the new build five months later.
But yet I was still dealing with the pain of all that stress that we went through.
God's timing was not mine.
Although he answered some prayers, not all of them had been answered yet.
David comes to the end of the psalm and he comes back to this idea of parallelism again.
He says, for the Lord's namesake, preserve my life.
In your righteousness, bring my soul out of trouble.
David wants to make sure that God is getting the glory for the rescue that's coming.
That's a true sign of revival in David's life because he's been changed by God.
His last statement is, for I am your servant.
David has laid it all out before God.
And he's resting in the hope of God that he will work all things out.
But, even if they don't, I feel as though this statement still says that he will keep his faith in God no matter what.
Look at the language change in verse 12.
I love this.
It says, in your steadfast love you will cut off my enemies.
You will destroy the adversaries of my soul.
God can do this and he will do this.
And David says, I know this about you.
I can trust that this is going to happen at some time.
It's an affirmative statement.
He will do it.
We may not see it on earth.
But that doesn't change God's character at all.
It still will happen.
Because of God.
He is who he is.
I have experienced God's faithfulness in healing about a year and a half after being in our new home.
It is now one of the works of God's hand in my life that I hold onto and I ponder and I think about when I am facing new difficulties and challenges.
So in closing today, our takeaway, the one thing I want you to take home is knowing the character of God so that it changes us and we can boldly come to the throne room when we're in trouble just as David did in Psalm 143.
A living encounter with God will leave us changed.
So I have a few questions for you to ponder today.
So, are we sensitive to his favor upon us?
Does his presence affect our daily lives, our decisions, our actions, our prayers?
Do we spend the time and meditate on the work of his hands?
Am I aware?
The worship team is going to play a song this morning.
If you know the words, I encourage you to sing them.
Use them as a prayer this morning.
If not, if you don't know the words, just allow it to minister to you.
Just let it sweep over you.
Spend time reflecting on the goodness of God in your life.
The prayer team will also be available if you would like prayer.
Give yourself this morning the freedom to get into a posture that reflects how you feel.
Allow your physical position to affect your spiritual position and vice versa.
Come, Holy Spirit.
There's nothing worth more that will ever come close.
No thing can compare.
You're our living hope.
Your presence, Lord.
Nothing worth more
That will ever come close
Nothing can compare
You're our living hope
Your presence is yours
I've tasted and seen
Of the sweetest of loves
Where my heart becomes free
And my shame is undone
In your presence, Lord
Holy Spirit, you are welcome
Come flood this place
And fill the atmosphere
Your glory, God, is what our hearts long for
To be overcome
By your presence, Lord
Your presence, Lord
Let us become more aware
Of your presence
Let us experience the glory of your goodness
Let us become more aware of your presence
Let us experience the glory of your goodness, Lord
Let us become more aware of your goodness, Lord
Holy Spirit, you are welcome here
Come flood this place and fill the atmosphere
Your glory, God, is what our hearts long for
Let us become more aware of your goodness, Lord
I hear some rough thoughts and ideas about it a few weeks ago
As she's just sharing her concepts and the things God's been teaching her
I can't even take credit for it because I don't think it was me
I think it was somebody else
I'm not going to give them public credit because it would go to their head
But they brought this image, this famous image on the ceiling of the Sistine Chapel
The hand of God, are you guys familiar with it?
God fully extending his hand
And Adam in the picture, it looks kind of like he's fully extending his hand
But if you take a closer look, it's slightly withdrawn
And as Jill was talking, I just kept coming back to that image
And thinking like how many of us really say, God, we want to be aware of your goodness
We want to meditate on what your spirit's doing
We want you to move and work
And yet there's parts of us that we're still holding back
And we're like, we're wondering why God isn't showing up and doing the thing that we see him do in others' lives
And I just can't help but wonder how many of us are still just something is holding us back
Whether it's an ongoing sin or anxiety about something or fear or a broken relationship that needs to be mended
That we're not mending
I don't know what it is, but I can't help but think there are some of us in this room that we want God to show up
But we're not offering ourselves fully to him
He's extended, he's waiting for us to fully extend
And the other thing I thought
For those of us that are fully extended
If you take that image, you fully extend, it's their fingers are touching
Subtle
And God often speaks in a whisper
When we want an earthquake
And so I think some of us, we need to be encouraged
Yes, we're fully extended
But we want God to grab us by the shoulders and shake us
And in his loving kindness and in the presence of his spirit
He's speaking to us in a whisper
A gentle touch
And that's what Joe reminded us of this morning
We need to be aware
We need to pay attention
We need to look for God's presence all around us
Because sometimes it's not going to be as obvious as we want it to be
Sometimes it's going to be gentle and subtle
Oftentimes it's going to be gentle and subtle
So wherever you're at this morning
I pray that these words would challenge, convict, and encourage
That if you're not fully extended
That today you would do the work
This week you would do the work
To make sure that you are fully extending your arm to God
And if you're there and you're waiting for God
To just show up and answer a huge prayer
Or do a huge thing
I just remind you that sometimes on this side of eternity
God's presence, his moving spirit
Isn't as obvious
As we'd like it to be
We have to be aware
We have to surround ourselves in Christian community
Where they can show us things that God's doing in our life
That we can't see because of our own struggles
So my prayer for us this week
Holy Spirit, make us more aware of your presence
Remove all of the obstacles
All of the rebellion
All of the withholding
Make us more aware
For your glory, for our good
For the good of our neighbors
It's in Jesus' name I pray
Amen
Go in peace, church
guitar solo
Thank you.